# GABRIELA SEWDHAN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER AND DATA SCIENTIST

#### **PROFILE**

BSc. In Computer Science and Psychology.

Experienced Software Engineer and Data
Scientist with a strong background in algorithms and software design, and advanced knowledge in Python and C++. Talented at working effectively in collaborative and self-motivated environment.

#### CONTACT

+1(868)496-5529

12 A, Sunset Avenue, Dumfries Road, Rambert Village, Trinidad and Tobago

gabiems13@gmail.com

### **SKILLS**

C++, Matlab, Python:

Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, OpenCV, ROS, Knowledgeable in software and algorithm design, data structures and software testing

Software Development in Linux, Hardware programming using Raspberry Pi and Arduino

Practised in Git, JIRA and Continuous
Integration

Sever-Side Skills: SQL, Docker and Server-side programming with Python, GoLang and NodeJS.

Knowledgeable in AutoCAD and SolidWorks

Data Science: regression models, Pandas, NumPy, Data Visualization with Plotly, Seaborn and Matplotlib

Amazon Web Services, including Serverless
Deployment (and YAML) and CloudFormation,
EC2, Elastic Container Service, Amazon Lex.
Experienced in Cloud Infrastructure.

Web and App Development: HTML5, JavaScript,
React Native and Expo, Ionic Framework,
ReactJS, PreactJS, Django

Adept at explaining complex topics to individuals of various technical backgrounds.

Able to effectively disperse tasks to project members that best suit their skills, and interests.

### **IMPORTANT LINKS**

Website - <a href="https://gabrielazoe.me/">https://github.com/GabrielaSewdhan</a>
LinkedIn - <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabriela-sewdhan-3ba495120/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabriela-sewdhan-3ba495120/</a>

### **REFERENCES**

Professor Patrick Hosein, Senior Lecturer,
Founder and Director, *UWI | TTLAB*+1 (858) 229-3651

Major Pernel Roberts, Senior Manager,
Strategic Analytics and Performance, *TSTT*+1 (868) 686-0782

**Amera Corporation** +1 (868) 734-2113

Kevin Ramnath, Chief Electrical Engineer,

Louis Kinley, Chief Technical Officer, *Persisto*Labs
+1 (868) 343-9638

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## DATA SCIENTIST AND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER @ TELECOMMUNICATION SERVICES OF TRINIDAD AND TOBAGO

November 2019 - September 2020

- Employed a recommender system to improve customer retention and long-term profit
  optimization via recommending and creating personalizing bundles.
- Developed an Admin interface for managing users, roles and permissions.
- Performed extensive analysis on team and organisation productivity data via aiding in the development of a Figure of Metric (FOM) measurement, mathematical model, and a Productivity Dashboard during COVID-19.
- Conducted Bi-weekly Programming and Data Science workshops.

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AND TESTER @ U.W.I DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE AND INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

July 2019 - August 2019

- Fully tested an existing system (UWI ETC) according to Campus IT Services Standards.
- Developed and implemented a volunteer tracking system and CRUD event system for UWI ETC using PHP, XAMPP and MS SQL Server.
- Gained further experience in team management, Agile and SCRUM methodologies.

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AND DATA SCIENTIST @ TECHNOLOGIES PERSISTO TECHNOLOGIES

August 2018 - October 2018

- Developed various software modules with a stringent and well-documented Git workflow, worked on deploying these microservices to Amazon Web Services.
  - Used ElasticSearch to scan newly signed up users against a DynamoDB database of blacklisted individuals scraped from various sites.
  - Developed a dispute resolution system for buyers and sellers.
- Gained practical experience in Cloud infrastructure and deployment, React Native app development, as well as created a chatbot using Amazon Lex.

### **EDUCATION**

BSc. Computer Science @ University of the West Indies, St. Augustine September 2016 - May 2020

#### **First Class Honors**

Full-stack development, optimization, software implementation of algorithms, Git workflow, machine learning and project management were practiced throughout, during course projects.

BSc. (Special) Psychology @ University of the West Indies, St. Augustine

September 2013 - August 2016

**First Class Honors** 

Research Paper: "Examining the Psychological Well-being of Cancer Survivors"

Supervisor: Dr. Jannel Phillip

### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

WSIS Forum HackAgainstHunger

QuickRental [2019]

A fully fledged apartment rental and social network app designed for U.W.I students via ReactNative and Expo.

DadliHack 2.0 Hackathon [2019]

**AntiPlasti:** Leveraging the Raspberry Pi, Cloud Technologies and React, in Detecting Oceanic Plastics and Waste using Image Recognition.

Bengaluru Tech Summit 2019 [2019]

"Innovation & Impact: Bengaluru Palace, Bengaluru, India"

PiDronics: Automated Hydrononics Control System to Increase Effectiveness Wit

[2018]

**PiDronics**: Automated Hydroponics Control System to Increase Effectiveness With Limited Resources and to diagnose plants using Image recognition

P-React [2018]

Image recognition with TensorFlow-lite was used to analyse body language and determine threatening poses.

## DCIT, UWI Robotics Bootcamp Mentor [2017/2018]

Volunteered as a senior mentor where I assisted in organizing the camp, contributing to the code and assisted students in programming a raspberry pi robot, particularly on the use of inceptionv3 for image recognition, epspeak for voice and the distance sensors to measure distance. Students were able to successfully program the robot to solve a maze, detect objects and dance.

Telios Code Jam [2017]

**MET-Oracle**: Using Machine Learning to Improve City Resilience and Awareness to Extreme Weather Conditions Due to Global Warming

International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) [2017]

DCIT Runtime Competition [2017]

## RESEARCH PROJECTS

**Eva-Ling:** Evaluating and Developing Speech Recognition for Caribbean Dialect [2018]

Companion Bot: [2020 - Now]

Recognising physiological and psychological issues via body language and facial cues with a neural network and adapting to the user's personality to form a companion that provides support and coping mechanisms for mental illnesses.

## AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

- Star Scholar, UWI Development and Endowment Fund
- Association of Female Executives of Trinidad and Tobago (AFETT)
- CIBC FirstCaribbean International Bank Scholarship